<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basic Concepts around Internet on VR</title>
    <link>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Basic Concepts around Internet on VR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:47:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet</title>
      <link>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:47:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/internet/</guid>
      <description>What is Internet? Internet is global network of billions of electronic devices and computer. It is possible to access almost any information, communicate wit anyone in world using internet.
How does Internet work? Internet is global network of physical cables/optical fibres which directly/indirectly connect all the electronice devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS</title>
      <link>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:47:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/dns/</guid>
      <description>What is DNS and how it works? DNS : Domain Naming System All the electonice devices connected to internet communicate to each other via a sequence of numbers called ipaddresses. Since it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for humans to remember these IPAddresses, there is a central server which translates the requested resource name to an ip address. It&amp;rsquo;s like a phonebook with domain name and ipaddresses.
Types of DNS Servers  DNS Recursive servers  These are provided by ISP provider (internet providers), which assign an ipaddress to one&amp;rsquo;s machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browsers</title>
      <link>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:47:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/be-developer-roadmap/internet-basics/browsers/</guid>
      <description>What are browsers and how do they work? A browser is an application which helps user to view a website.
It mainly consists of
 User Interface [the UI of a browser which lets user enter a webaddress, refresh etc] Rendering Engine  The engine where DOM is converted to a webpage as we see it This layer is responsible for making all network requests, parse the html and request for more resources required   Browser Engine [Maintains communication between Browser UI and Rendering Engine] Network [To get data from various sources] Javascript Interpretor  It provides interpretor for javascript which is used to provide various interactive features on the webpage   Data Storage [for storing cache,cookies, history etc]  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>